As I said...
言ったはずだ｡
The systems of this world
are under our control.
この世界のｼｽﾃﾑは
すでに 我々が掌握したと｡
我を倒すことは すなわち➡
Defeating me will destroy this world.
この世界を滅ぼすことと同じ｡
Will you still attempt to defeat me?
それでも 我を倒せるか？
ﾌｯ… ぬしらに たまが殺せるか｡
Can you kill Tama?
ﾌﾌﾌ… ｱｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊ！
Firebane!!
[Note: Original text, "Begirama" is a spell
from the game Dragon Quest series.]
(銀時)とりゃ～！
["And Into the Legend..."]
Ow, ow, ow...
ｲﾀﾀﾀ！ ちょっ 待って
ちょっ 待って！ ﾀﾝﾏ！
Wait! Hold on! Time-out!
おりゃ！
え？ ちょっ 待って！
No, wait! Wait!
えっ 聞いてた？ ぬし
我の話 聞いてた？ ｱﾊﾞｶﾑ！
Weren't you listening to what
I was saying?! Open!
Huh? Something about offering
us half of the world?
あぁ 世界の半分
くれてやろうとか そういうﾔﾂ？
And it doesn't matter if we pick yes or no
because we still end up fighting, right?
どうせ はい いいえ
どっち答えても 戦闘だろ？
いいよ もう そういうの
めんどくせえから｡
Forget it. Too much of a hassle.
どこの 竜王の話？ ｺｲﾂ
まったく人の話聞いてないよ！
Wouldn't that be the Dragonlord?
He didn't listen to a single word I said.
魔王の話は
総じて 長すぎるんだ｡
The Archfiend always talks too much.
だいたい ｵﾚは
流し読みすることにしてる…｡
I usually just skim through.
何しとるんだ！ ｷｻﾏ！
What do you think you're doing?!
Any damage to the Archfiend Tapir
will mean damage to Lady Tama!
獏大魔王を傷つけることは➡
たま様を傷つけることと
同じなんだぞ！
Aren't you capable of exercising discretion?!
もっと 慎重に動かんか！
Uh, you realize you just
indirectly attacked her?!
(新八)いや ｱﾝﾀも間接的に
ﾒﾁｬﾒﾁｬ攻撃してんですけど！
魔王 ﾎﾞﾛﾎﾞﾛですけど！
The Archfiend is completely beat-up?!
What do you think you're doing?!
何しやがんだ！ この野郎！
Get out of my way. Scram!
邪魔すんじゃねえよ
引っ込んでろ！
引っ込むのは ｷｻﾏだ！
You scram!
Hey!
おい～！ 魔王を前に
何やってんだ ｱﾝﾀらぁ！
What are you doing in
front of the Archfiend?!
Curse you...
おのれ この体が滅んでも
構わぬというのか？
So you do not care if this
body is destroyed?
なんて薄情なﾔﾂらだ｡
Heartless bastards...
And you call yourself heroes?!
それでも ｷｻﾏら 勇者か！
魔王に言われたくないんですけど｡
Like the Archfiend's in
any position to talk!
ｷｻﾏらが薄情なのは わかった｡
I can now see that you are big douches.
だが これを見ても
同じようにいくかな？
But will you be able to continue
after seeing this?
白血球王 ぬしは
父の顔を覚えているか？
Leukocyte King, do you remember
your father's face?
そう ぬしの父 先王ﾌｫﾙﾃｶﾞは
我との戦いの最中➡
Yes, your father, the previous
king, Fortega,
fell into the anus during
his battle with me
肛門に落下し
命を落としたのであったな｡
and lost his life.
だが もし ﾌｫﾙﾃｶﾞが生きてたら
どうする？
But what would you do if
Fortega were still alive?
我に食われ いまだ 我の中で
のたうち苦しみ➡
What would you do if he still lived in pain
within me after being consumed?
生きさらばえていたとしたら
どうする？
It can't be...
まさか… まさか ｷｻﾏ！
そう そのまさかだ…➡
You couldn't have...
Yes, exactly...
我が 息子…｡
My son...
Father!
父上～！
いや ちょっ 待て～！
Hey, wait! Hold up!
早すぎるだろ ｷｻﾏら！
You move too fast!
I didn't even get a chance
to reveal his father's face!
父上 まだ ちゃんと
顔見せてないよ！
しゃべりかけだったよ｡
しかも なんで今度は 全員参加!?
I was still talking!
And why is everybody
hitting me this time?!
We don't feel a thing when you
use the "I'm your father" setting.
(神楽)いきなり ﾊﾟｯと出て
父親設定とか出てきても➡
まったく 感情移入できないｱﾙ｡
たまさんより
全然やりやすいんで➡
This is much easier than beating Tama-san's face,
so I figured I'd use this chance to finish you.
今のうちに
やっつけておこうと思いまして｡
人の父親との悲劇の対面を
なんだと思ってんだ ｷｻﾏら！
Don't you people have any respect for this
tragic meeting between father and son?!
Nobody uses "the last boss is
your father" twist anymore.
父親が ﾗｽﾎﾞｽとか
今どき古り～いんだよ！
設定 練り直してこい ﾊﾞｶ野郎！
Come up with something better.
(３人)おっとっと…｡
おぉっ ぬぉ～っ！
ｺﾞﾎｯ ｺﾞﾎｯ… しまった！
Curses!
ｺﾝｾﾝﾄが抜けて ｼｽﾃﾑの接続が
遮断されてしまった！
I pulled the plug and we lost our
connection to the system!
ｺﾝｾﾝﾄ!? なに？
そんな適当なもんで➡
Plug?!
You people were controlling the system
with such a half-assed method?!
ｼｽﾃﾑ支配してたの!? ｱﾝﾀら！
This is it!
しめた！ たま様のｼｽﾃﾑと
分離した今なら➡
Now that he's disconnected
from Lady Tama's system,
たま様は 無傷のまま
獏大魔王を倒せるはず！
we can defeat the Archfiend Tapir
without harming Lady Tama!
This is our only chance!
ﾁｬﾝｽは 今しかない！ いくぞ！
Let's go!
(銀時たち)うぉ～っ！
Don't underestimate me, brats!
ﾅﾒるな！ こわっぱども！
ﾊｧ～ｯ！
うわっ！
うぅっ！
Your cheap appliance store security
measures can't possibly defeat me
高度なからくり技術を
食らい尽くし➡
超進化を遂げた我を➡
電気屋で 安売りしていそうな
ｷｻﾏら安いｾｷｭﾘﾃｨｰに➡
after I've consumed high-level technology
and undergone an extreme evolution!
倒せると思うてか！
I can no longer be considered a virus.
すでに 我は ｳｲﾙｽなどという
くだらぬ存在ではない｡
人智を超えた存在…➡
I have transcended human
understanding...
そう… 神！
Yes...
A god!
ｷｻﾏら人間など 遠く及ばない｡
A being you humans cannot cope with...
神とも呼べる 完璧な存在と
なりつつあるのだ｡
A perfect being known as a god!
A god...?
神？ ｶﾋﾞの間違いだろ？
God schmod.
ﾃﾒｴは こんなところより➡
You're supposed to be fighting
it out with some
腐ったﾊﾟﾝの上で ｲｰｽﾄ菌と
乳繰り合ってんのが➡
yeast cells on a rotten piece
of bread, Germfiend.
お似合いだぜ ﾊﾞｲｷﾝﾏﾝ！
そこは ﾃﾒｴの居場所じゃねえ！
This isn't where you belong.
Get the hell outta Tama-san.
たまさんから出ていけ｡
We won't allow you to contaminate
our friend any further.
This will be the last clean-up job!
ｺｲﾂが 最後の大掃除だ｡
いくぜ ﾃﾒｴら！
Let's go, guys!
Yeah!
おおっ！
Huh?
My body won't move the way I want it to.
Huh? Huh?
What's with Kagura?!
きゃ～ぐらちゅわは～ん？
なな… なんで？
Wh-Wh-Why?!
なんで神楽ちゃんが ﾄﾞｯﾄ絵に？
Why did Kagura-chan turn into pixels?!
いったいどういうことだ？
まさか神楽にまでｳｲﾙｽが？
Wh-What's going on here?
Don't tell me Kagura got
infected by the virus?
いや まさか そんなはずは…｡
That can't be it...
How could a human being be
infected by a computer virus...
生身の人間が ｺﾝﾋﾟｭｰﾀｳｲﾙｽに
感染するなんて｡
ﾌｯﾌｯ 言っただろう｡ すでに我は➡
As I said...
I am no longer a pathetic computer virus!
ｺﾝﾋﾟｭｰﾀｳｲﾙｽなどという
くだらぬ存在ではないと！
うわぁっ！
Shinpachi!
Shinpachi! You okay?!
新八 無事か？
なんとか｡
Somehow...
ちょん まり…｡
Shrunk
down...
あ あぁ… 足短っ！
M-M-My legs are short!
Looks like you're okay.
ﾌｩ どうやら大事ねえようだな｡
違うだろ！ 本体こっちぃ！
Like hell I am!
My body's over here!
足がこれ｡ なんでよりによって
こんな中途半端にぃ？
And my legs are like this!
Why was my transformation
so half-assed?!
こんなんだったら 全身やられた
ほうが まだよかった｡
I'd take a full body change over this!
え？ なにか変わった？
Huh? Something changed?
Didn't your body always
look like a Guntank?
[Note: Guntank is a weapon from
the anime series Gundam.]
もともと そんな感じじゃ
なかったっけ？ ｶﾞﾝﾀﾝｸ｡
Who are you calling a Guntank?!
誰がｶﾞﾝﾀﾝｸだ！
G-Gin-chan...
It's like... my body's like stone...
I can't move...
おい 神楽｡
しっかりしろ！
Hey, Kagura! Hang in there!
What is this?
なんだこれ？
徐々にﾄﾞｯﾄが侵食してくる｡
The pixels are advancing!
体がどんどん重くなってきてます｡
銀さん！
My body's getting heavier
and heavier, Gin-san!
Shinpachi!
新八｡
Help... Gin-chan...
Kagura!
神楽！
うわぁ 銀さん｡
なんとかしてください！
Gin-san! Do something!
Shintank!
新ﾀﾝｸ！
新ﾀﾝｸって誰よ！
Who's that supposed to be?!
Gin-chan...
M-My body is...
うわぁ 体が…｡
銀ちゃん…｡
Why are you standing around?
なにをﾓﾀﾓﾀしている｡
死にたいのか？
Do you want to die?
ｱｲﾂらは？
ﾑﾀﾞだ｡
They're...
It's no use.
They've been completely pixilated.
もう全身にﾄﾞｯﾄ化が進んでいる｡
ここは ひとまず退くぞ｡
We need to retreat for now!
神楽｡ 新ﾀﾝｸ！
Kagura! Shintank!
ﾌｯﾌｯ｡ 逃がさんぞ｡
I won't let you get away!
どうやら ﾔﾂがｳｲﾙｽ以上の力を
得たのは 本当のことらしい｡
It appears that he wasn't lying about having
more power than a normal virus.
ﾔﾂは急激な進化の過程で
ｵﾚたちだけじゃなく➡
His extreme evolution has given
him the power to control viruses,
生身の人間にまで
影響を与えるｳｲﾙｽを➡
制御する能力を得たようだ｡
which affect human beings
in addition to us programs.
You've gotta be kidding.
冗談だろ｡ 風呂に入らなすぎて➡
I've heard of an animator, who didn't take a bath
for so long that he had fungus on his penis,
ﾁﾝｺにｶﾋﾞ生えたｱﾆﾒｰﾀｰは
聞いたことあるが➡
but I've never heard of anyone getting
infected by a computer virus!
ｺﾝﾋﾟｭｰﾀｳｲﾙｽにやられたﾔﾂなんて
聞いたことねえぜ｡
うわぁっ！
It appears that you're running out of time.
どうやらｷｻﾏも
時間がないようだな｡
Your entire body will eventually
become pixels.
いずれﾄﾞｯﾄ化は 全身に回るぞ｡
なんでだ？
Why?!
Why is enemy fire always
concentrated here?!
なんで いつもｵﾚ
ここばっか集中砲火？
Because I haven't used
it for a long time?!
最近 全然使ってねえからか？
ｽﾈてんのか？
You upset?!
ｽﾈたいのはこっちだ｡ ﾊﾞｯｷｬﾛｰ！
治んのかこれ？ ｵﾚのﾁﾝｺ｡
I'm the one who's upset, moron!
Is my penis going to get better?!
新八と神楽は
元に戻るんだろうな？
Will Shinpachi and Kagura
ever recover?!
Just stay there.
ｷｻﾏは そこを動くな｡
あとはｵﾚがなんとかする｡
I'll handle the rest.
ｷｻﾏも｡ ｷｻﾏの仲間も｡
おい 待て｡
You and your friends...
Hey! Wait!
動くなと言っているんだ｡
I told you to stay there.
ｷｻﾏがいなくなったら いったい
これから誰が たま様を護る？
Who's going to protect
Lady Tama if you die?
ｷｻﾏがいなくなったら いったい
たま様がどれほど悲しむと思う？
How sad do you think Lady Tama
will be if you die here?
ｵﾚは たま様を
護るためだけに作られた｡
I was created for the sole purpose
of protecting Lady Tama.
護るものなど 他になにもない｡
I have nothing else to protect.
しょせん ｷｻﾏの代用品にすぎない｡
I am merely your substitute.
たま様のために死ぬのは
ｵﾚだけで十分だ｡
I should be the only one who
has to die for Lady Tama!
Forget...about...me...
((たま:せめて 彼だ… けでも
ここから 解放させ…))
At least try...to release...
him...from this...place...
Tama said the same thing to me.
同じことを言われたよ｡
たまにもよ｡
She told me to forget about
her and protect you.
自分のことはいい｡
ﾃﾒｴを護ってやってくれってよ｡
To release you from this place.
こっからﾃﾒｴを解放して
逃がしてやってくれって｡
だから ｵﾚは言ってやったんだ｡
That's why I told her,
ﾃﾒｴがもし
ｵﾚのよくできたｺﾋﾟｰなら➡
if you were really a copy of me,
そんなこと
望んじゃいねえだろうって｡
you would never want that.
ﾃﾒｴの護るもん ほっぽって
逃げ出すようなﾏﾈは➡
Even if you died, you'd never dream of running
away and leaving you in charge behind.
死んでも望まねえ… ってよ｡
どうやら
ｵﾚの買いかぶりだったようだな｡
Guess I overestimated you.
大事なもん人に押し付けて
早々にﾘﾀｲｱか…｡
You're dumping what's important off on
someone else and stepping down?
ｵﾚはｷｻﾏのｺﾋﾟｰだ｡
I am your copy.
It doesn't matter if I die. As long as
you live, more copies can be made.
たとえ死しても
お前が生きていれば➡
また いくらでも複製される｡
ｵﾚは ﾃﾒｴのような出来の悪いｺﾋﾟｰ
持った覚えはねえよ｡
I don't remember having
such a pathetic copy.
ﾃﾒｴじゃ ｵﾚの代わりは務まらねえ｡
You wouldn't have a chance
of taking my place.
ｵﾚもﾃﾒｴの代わりを務めるなんざ
まっぴら ごめんこうむるぜ｡
And I absolutely refuse to take yours.
誰も代わりなんざ
務まりゃしねえんだよ｡
Nobody can take anybody's place.
お前の代わりなんざ➡
There isn't a person in this world
that could take your place.
世界のどこにも
いやしねえんだよ｡
ｵﾚから生まれようが
ﾂﾗが同じだろうが関係ねえ｡
It doesn't matter if you were based
on me or have the same face.
ここでずっと たまを思い続けて
護り続けてきたのは➡
You're the one who's devoted yourself to
protecting Tama this whole time, not me.
ｵﾚじゃなくて お前だろうが｡
たまにとっちゃ
お前は ｺﾋﾟｰでも代用品でもねえ｡
As far as Tama's concerned,
you're no copy or substitute.
ずっと自分を支えてくれた➡
You're someone who's always
been there for her...
交換なんてきかねえ
大事な仲間の一人なんだ｡
A precious, irreplaceable friend...
ﾃﾒｴが たまを
本当に大事に思ってんなら➡
If you truly care about Tama,
くたばるなんて
二度と言うんじゃねえ｡
never talk about dying again.
ﾃﾒｴを 代用品なんて
二度と言うんじゃねえ｡
Never call yourself a substitute again.
ｹﾝｶも もうやめだ｡
I'm done fighting with you.
生き残って
仲よく一杯やろうや… 兄弟！
Let's survive and have a
drink together, brother.
腐った汁など
汚らわしくて飲む気もせん｡
I have no interested in fermented juice.
六甲の天然水なら つきあおう…｡
It's a different story if you have
Delicious Water from Rokkou, brother!
[Note: Delicious Water from Rokkou is a brand
name of mineral water from House Foods.]
兄弟！
♪♪～
いいか ここでﾔﾂを止めなければ➡
Got it?
If we don't stop him here,
たま様だけじゃない
お前たちの世界にまで➡
Lady Tama won't be his only victim.
The viruses will invade your entire world.
ｳｲﾙｽは侵攻を始める｡
時間はない｡
ｷｻﾏの全身がﾄﾞｯﾄになる前に➡
We have no time.
We have to stop him before your
entire body turns into pixels!
なんとしても ﾔﾂを止めるんだ｡
ｵﾚたち二人で
すべてを終わらせるんだ！
The two of us will end
this once and for all!
ﾌｯ… こわっぱどもが｡
Foolish brats...
ようやく
死ぬ覚悟ができたようだな｡
I see you're finally ready to die.
これで すべてが終わる｡
This will be the end for all.
すべては 我らに染まる｡
All shall be darkened by me.
白は消え去り➡
White shall vanish,
and everything shall be crushed in black!
すべては
黒く塗りつぶされるのだ！
塗りつぶされんのは
ﾃﾒｴだよ ﾊﾞｲｷﾝﾏﾝ｡
You're the one who's going
to get crushed, Germfiend.
これで最後だ 獏｡
This is the end, Tapir.
白と黒 どちらが生き残るか｡
We shall see if white or black survives!
Time to settle this once and for all!
白黒 はっきり
つけようじゃねえか！
ほざけ 虫けらども！
Cease your prattle, worms!
Return to the sea of pixels!
ﾄﾞｯﾄの海へと帰るがいい！
Let's go!
いくぞ～！
Release all of your power!
すべての力を解放しろ！
この一撃に…｡
Put everything
すべてを込めろ！ いけ～っ!!
into this single blow!
Go!
What?! They stopped my wave?!
なに!? 我が波動を止めた！
うおぉ～っ!!
おのれ 我と張り合おうというか！
こざかしい！
Curse you!
Are you contesting me?!
Crafty bastards!
I'll crush you and your impertinent wave!
その ちょこざいな波動ごと
押し潰してくれる！
うおぉ～っ!!
ぐっ…｡
体が… ﾄﾞｯﾄ化していく｡
My body is turning into pixels...
ﾌﾊﾊﾊﾊ！ 止められぬ！
I cannot be stopped!
誰にも我を止められぬわ ﾌﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
Nobody can stop me!
こいつは長くはもたねえぜ｡
We won't last long against this.
このままじゃ二人とも
仲よくお陀仏だ！
At this rate, we'll both
be kicking the bucket.
いけ｡
Go.
What?
I'll hold him back.
ここは ｵﾚがおさえてみせる｡
ｵﾚが獏を引きつけている間に
ｷｻﾏがﾔﾂを倒せ！
While I distract him, you defeat him!
今ならﾔﾂは無防備だ｡
He should be defenseless right now.
This is our only chance to defeat him!
ﾔﾂを倒すのは
今をおいて他にはない！
How can you possibly hold him off yourself when
the two of us can barely cope, moron?
二人がかりでやっとのもんを➡
どうして ﾃﾒｴ一人で
おさえられるってんだ ﾊﾞｶ野郎！
I have a plan.
策はある｡ それに
この足では ｵﾚはもう動けん｡
And I can't move with my legs like this.
ﾔﾂの元まで行けるのは
もう ｷｻﾏだけだ｡
You're the only one who
can reach him now.
早くしろ！
ｷｻﾏが まだ動けるうちに！
Hurry it up!
While you can still move!
ﾃﾒｴ… 約束は忘れちゃいねえな！
Bastard...
You better not have forgotten our promise.
案ずるな｡
あんな者に遅れはとらんさ｡
Do not worry.
He cannot hurt me.
ｵﾚを誰だと思っている…｡
Who do you think I am?!
Gintoki Sakata.
坂田銀時…
ｷｻﾏから生まれた男だぞ！
A man based off you.
《兄弟… 友達…》
Brother...
Friend...
I earned many titles for a mere copy...
《たかがｺﾋﾟｰ｡ 短い間でいろいろと
呼び名がついたものだ》
《だが 何と呼ばれようとも
自分の役割は➡
But no matter what I'm called,
I cannot lose sight of my role...my duty...
自分のなすべきことは
見失うわけにはいかない｡
たま様… 申し訳ありません｡
Lady Tama, forgive me.
My duty is not to live,
ｵﾚの役目は生きることではない
あなたを護ることなんです｡
it is to protect you.
誰かのために生きる… ｵﾚには
そんなことできないけれど➡
I cannot live for the sake of another,
but grant me the right to die for a friend...
せめて 死ぬるときは友がため！
兄弟がために
散らせてください！》
To die for my brother!
ぐわ～!!
ﾊﾞｶな… ﾔﾂの力が急激に…｡
Impossible...
His power is surging..
How does he have so much power left?!
いったい どこに
こんな力が残って…｡
力ならば残っているさ｡
I have plenty of power left...
My very life...
このｵﾚの… 命そのものが!!
ま… まさかｷｻﾏ！
生命ｴﾈﾙｷﾞｰをすべて放出して…｡
C-Could you be releasing
all of your life energy?
Impossible!
ﾊﾞｶな！ そんなことをすれば
ｷｻﾏは… ｷｻﾏは～!!
If you do that, you'll...
You'll...!
ぐわ～!!
ｷｻﾏらｳｲﾙｽごときに
この白血球王が➡
You think you damn viruses
can defeat the Leukocyte King?
Defeat...
この… 坂田銀時が！
(２人)負けるか～!!
Gintoki Sakata?! Never!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]体内のみなさまに
お知らせします｡
Attention to everybody inside this body.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]体内を汚染していたｳｲﾙｽは
無事 駆逐されました｡
The virus, which infected this
body, has been destroyed.
This body will now engage
in reparations.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]これより体内は
復旧作業に入ります｡
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]生き残っている
ｾｷｭﾘﾃｨｰのみなさまは➡
All surviving security members
should take a vacation from their
regular duties to make babies.
通常の業務をお休みして
子作りに励んでください｡
The surviving viruses should change
into white bodysuits at once.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]生き残ったｳｲﾙｽのみなさまは
すぐに白ﾀｲﾂに着替えてください｡
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]あなたたちは
すでに私たちの支配下です｡
You are already under our control.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]子作りを手伝ってください｡
Please assist with making babies.
悪いな 約束を守れなくて｡
Sorry I couldn't keep my promise...
いいかげんなのは ﾃﾞﾌｫﾙﾄなんだ｡
ｷｻﾏ譲りでな｡
I'm irresponsible by default.
I got that from you.
どうやらそうらしいな｡
ｵﾚも たまとの約束 破っちまった｡
Looks like it.
I broke my promise to Tama.
至極遺憾だ｡
こんなﾎﾟﾝｺﾂになってしまうとは｡
It's extremely regrettable.
I never expected to become
a piece of junk.
ｷｻﾏらが来るまでは
ｵﾚは実に優秀なｾｷｭﾘﾃｨｰだった｡
I was an excellent security measure
before you all came.
A hero guarding the princess.
まさに姫を護る勇者｡
I would have been happy to throw
my life away to protect Lady Tama.
たま様を護るためなら
喜んで命を投げ打った｡
それが まさか姫様どころか➡
And yet I gave my life to save this stupid
party instead of the princess...
くだらんﾊﾟｰﾃｨｰのために
命を捨てることになるとはな｡
以前は死ぬことなど
何とも思わなかったが➡
Before, I wouldn't have thought
twice about dying...
今は もう少し… 生きたい｡
But now...
I want to live a little longer...
もう少し たま様と ｷｻﾏらと➡
I wouldn't have minded a little more adventuring
with Lady Tama and the lot of you...
冒険するのも
悪くなかったように思える｡
白血球王さん…｡
Leukocyte King-san...
死しても代わりなど
いくらでもいる 代用品のｵﾚが➡
For such words to come out of
an easily replaced substitute...
こんなことを…
ｷｻﾏらのせいで…｡
It's all your fault...
どうやら ｵﾚは 完全に
どこか壊れてしまったらしい｡
It appears that I've completely
broken down.
壊れてなんかいねえよ｡
代用品なんかじゃねえよ｡
You haven't broken down.
You're no substitute.
ﾃﾒｴは ｵﾚなんぞより
よっぽど たいした野郎だ｡
You're a much better guy than I am.
護るべきもんを
きっちり守り通したんだ｡
You protected what you needed to.
I don't just mean Tama.
たまだけじゃねえ｡
ｵﾚたちの命まで｡
You also protected our lives.
だから 死ぬんじゃねえ｡
So don't die.
ﾀﾞﾁなんぞのために
死ぬんじゃねえ！
Don't die for your friends.
ﾀﾞﾁのために…
ｵﾚたちのために生きろ｡
You have to live for your friends, for us...
ｷｻﾏらがいれば たま様は大丈夫だ｡
それに ｵﾚは もう…｡
Lady Tama will be fine with
you people around.
Besides, I can no longer...
Gintoki-sama, everybody...
Thank you for protecting the
Leukocyte King all this time.
It's Tama-san! Tama-san's voice!
これは たまさん!?
たまさんの声だ！
たまｱﾙ！ 無事治ったｱﾙか!?
どこね？ どこにいるね？
It's Tama. Are you okay now?
Where are you? Where are you at?
Here. Over here.
Here. I'm right here.
ぬおっ ちっさ！
た たま様…｡
Tiny!
L-Lady Tama...
What are you doing, Tama?
Why are you so tiny?
何やってるｱﾙか たま！
なんで こんなちっちゃく…｡
My system has not completely recovered,
but I was able to send a pixel copy over.
(たま)白血球王 今まで長い間
私を護ってくれてありがとう｡
Leukocyte King, thank you for protecting
me for such a long time.
Now it is my turn to save you.
今度は 私が
あなたを助ける番です｡
たまさん！ まさか あなた！
Tama-san, can you...
I shall enter the Leukocyte King's
body and repair him.
Leukocyte King, I will not let you die.
た… たま様…｡
L-Lady Tama...
だったら 私たちも行くｱﾙ！
ﾓｼｬｽ銀ちゃんに借りがあるね！
We're coming along then.
We owe the Moshasu Gin-chan.
[Note: Moshasu is a spell from Dragon Quest
to transform one of the characters in the party.]
いや でも ﾎﾞｸら
どうやって体内に入るの？
Uh, but how are we supposed
to go inside him?
この体の大きさじゃ入れな…｡
We're too big to enter...
(源外)てや～っ!!
そう言うと思ってな➡
I knew you'd say that.
ｵﾚも 打ち出の大槌Ｚを
持ってきてやったぞい！
That's why I brought the magic mallet Z.
さぁ 小さくなりたいﾔﾂは
そこに直れ！
Okay! Line up if you want to be shrunk!
片っぱしから
ぶん殴ってやるから！
I'll smash you all good!
Th-They're...
ｱ… ｱｲﾂら…｡
そういうことさ｡
There you have it.
もう ﾃﾒｴの命は➡
Your life is no longer
yours to throw away.
ﾃﾒｴの好き勝手できるところに
ありゃしねえんだよ｡
お前は もう
たまを護るだけの存在じゃない｡
You're more than someone
who protects Tama.
お前が護ったぶんだけ お前を
護ってくれる存在がいるのさ｡
All the protecting you've done has led to
people who will protect you in return.
わらわら わらわら…｡
All squirmy-like...
Just like a white blood cell.
まるで 白血球みてえだろ｡
つくづく やっかいな男の
ｺﾋﾟｰに生まれたものだ｡
I just had to be the copy
of such a difficult man.
こんなときになっても➡
Even now, I can't offer any words
of gratitude or tears...
感謝の言葉も 涙も➡
ﾛｸに出てきやしない｡
What would you do in this situation?
どうするんだ？
お前なら こんなとき｡
笑うのさ｡
Smile.
[The End?]
Enemy spotted.
敵影確認！
未確認の新種のｳｲﾙｽです！
An unidentified new virus.
とてつもない大軍が
こちらに押し寄せてきます！
An extremely large army is
advancing on our position!
Unbelievable...
なんということだ…｡
And we haven't recovered from
the Tapir invasion yet...
まだ 獏による侵略の傷跡も
消えておらぬというのに…｡
この残り少ない手勢で
太刀打ちできるのか…｡
Will we be able to fight them off
with our meager numbers?
What is there to fear?
何を臆する？
たとえ この地から
白き旗が消えうせても➡
Every white flag may vanish from this land,
but our army will not fight on its own.
我らは孤軍ではない｡
たとえ 軍が壊滅しようとも
我らは一人ではない｡
Our army may be destroyed,
but we will not be alone.
所違えど 我らと同じ志を持ち
戦う者たちがいる｡
Though we may be in different places,
there are others who carry
the same will and fight.
御旗の色は違えど➡
Though they may fly
a different color flag,
我らと同じ 白き気高き魂を持った
仲間たちがいる｡
we have comrades who possess
the same proud, white spirit!
たとえ 100万の軍勢たりとも➡
Even an army one million strong
この白は染められぬ！
cannot darken this white!
ゆくぞ～!!
Tally ho!
[Preview]
It could happen to anyone...
Even to an animated character...
As long as genes, unhealthy behavior, stress,
and other various factors are involved,
["You Don't Know What You've Got Till It's Gone"]
all people have a chance of going bald.
[Next week's episode is a two-parter. The other part is "You'll Get Sued If All You Do is Copy Others."]
[Two cat burglars break into Odd Jobs followed by tons of unexpected visitors.]
[See you next time.]
♬『ゼッコーチョー！』
♬～